Dakota Rennemann

Software Engineer

Forward-thinking Software Engineer with background working productively in dynamic environments. Experienced with using React.js and Node.js as well as C# and.Net to develop Full Stack solutions. Proud team player focused on achieving project objectives with speed and accuracy.

Work History

2020-12 - Software Engineer Current

Infotech, Gainesville, Florida

Worked with team members to develop and test enhancements and fix reported bugs using best practices of TDD/BDD. Helped manage and automate parts of the CI/CD process to improve code quality and ease of deployment using Jenkins and Github actions.

2020-05 - Software Developer Intern

2021-12 Infotech, Gainesville, Florida

Developed Github actions bot to automate 30% of the code review process. Continued to push support for automation through Github actions and became teams subject matter expert.

2020-01 - Undergraduate Student Researcher

2021-01 University Of Florida, Gainsville, Florida

Created the infrastructure to scale out projects to thousands of users as well as logging relevant research data. This included automatic Developed main systems to integrate Google's Blockly project into a user-facing web application.

2018-05 - Software Developer Intern

Perspecta, Melbourne, Florida

Worked on upgrading aging monolith web systems into more modern modular systems. Learned how to work on an AGILE focused team and follow good design processes.

Education

2018-08

2020-12

2017-08 - Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

University of Florida - Gainesville, FL

- Taught students best practices in web development as a Teachers Assistant for Software Engineering for multiple semesters.
- Officer in the UF Open Source club. Contributed to multiple community lead open source projects such as a React website, python discord bot, and multiple MERN stack template repositories.

Contact

Address

Gainesville, FL, 32608

Phone

(321) 806-0676

E-mail

rennemannd@gmail.com

Skills

Node.js

Very Good

Excellent

AWS

Good

Jenkins

Good

C#

Good

Python

Very Good

MySql

Good

Jest/QUnit

Very Good

BD/TD Development

Very Good

Certifications

2021-11 AWS Cloud Practitioner

2021-12 AWS Developer (In Progress Planned for December Exam)

Notable Projects

CaSMM Cloud Based Programming Interface

University of Florida Human Computer Interaction Research Lab **Description:** A block based programming interface meant to teach 5th and 6th grade students the fundamentals of programming through science and making. Built to allow students to connect to and program Arduino boards entirely from the browser without any downloads by handling compiling in a series of compile servers hosted through AWS.

Technologies: React.js, Node.js, Docker, AWS ELB, Strapi, MongoDB

AASHTOWare Project

Infotech

Description: A suite of technology meant to be used by transportation construction groups. Meant to help with the entire process from contract bidding to managing construction. Contains eleven major modules each of which contain major functionality such as a cost estimation system.

Technologies: C#, .Net, MySql, Javascript, QUnit, Jenkins (Groovy), Python3, Specflow

MERN-Heroku-Template

Description: A Github repository setup to help students at the University of Florida start with no knowledge and deploy a full stack MERN application using Heroku. This includes in depth explanations of most aspects of deployment.

Technologies: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Heroku